<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on relax, you're probably doing fine</title><link>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on relax, you're probably doing fine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 17:15:23 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No for Each Item in Array in Terraform</title><link>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/no-for-each-item-in-array-in-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 17:15:23 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/no-for-each-item-in-array-in-terraform/</guid><description>I was importing my team&amp;rsquo;s PagerDuty setup into Terraform today. There are 6 people in PagerDuty users so I thought, I would create locals block with users as array of map containing each name and email. Then I&amp;rsquo;d feed local.users into pagerduty_user resource using for_each.
locals { users = [ { name = &amp;#34;John Doe&amp;#34; email = &amp;#34;john@company.com&amp;#34; }, { name = &amp;#34;Somebody&amp;#34; email = &amp;#34;somebody@company.com&amp;#34; }, // ... ] } resource &amp;#34;pagerduty_user&amp;#34; &amp;#34;users&amp;#34; { for_each = local.</description></item><item><title>Konfigurasi Replikasi di PostgreSQL 11</title><link>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/konfigurasi-replikasi-di-postgresql-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 13:45:33 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/konfigurasi-replikasi-di-postgresql-11/</guid><description>Yay PostgreSQL 11 baru saja keluar bulan lalu (lihat di sini untuk diskusi HN). Yuk kita coba mengkonfigurasi replikasi di PostgreSQL 11.
Replikasi di PostgreSQL Replikasi di PostgreSQL didasarkan pada teknologi Write Ahead Log (WAL). Fungsi WAL sangat simpel. Seperti namanya, WAL menjadikan PostgreSQL untuk menulis log sebelum setiap perubahan yang terjadi. Perubahan data tidak akan dilakukan sebelum WAL berhasil disimpan ke storage. Log ini berisi perubahan yang dilakukan kepada PostgreSQL.</description></item><item><title>Running Ethereum Private Network</title><link>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/running-ethereum-private-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 12:38:12 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/running-ethereum-private-network/</guid><description>One good way to understand Ethereum is by creating your own Ethereum private network. I have been trying to understand Ethereum in the past few weeks and I learned a lot of things just by creating it. I&amp;rsquo;ll now write down what I got from creating Ethereum private network. And I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post as I learn new things&amp;hellip; hopefully
First of all, Ethereum client works by connecting to a network specified by its networkid.</description></item><item><title>Setup PostgreSQL on Ubuntu 16.04</title><link>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/setup-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 21:33:58 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://asasmoyo.github.io/blog/setup-postgresql/</guid><description>Install PostgreSQL By default, Ubuntu 16.04 instance has already postgresql package, but it is pretty out of date. You can still install latest version available (currently 9.6) by adding PostgreSQL repo into your ubuntu instance.
First create a file at /etc/apt/sources.list.d/postgres.list with this content
deb http://apt.postgresql.org/pub/repos/apt/ xenial-pgdg main Then run these commands to install PostgreSQL signing key and also install PostgreSQL 9.6
wget --quiet -O - https://www.postgresql.org/media/keys/ACCC4CF8.asc | sudo apt-key add - sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install postgresql-9.</description></item></channel></rss>